[
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('initiate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "European Parliament's Industry, Research and Energy Committee (ITRE)",
    "context": "\"The EIT Chairman was equally invited for an exchange of views at the European Parliament's Industry, Research and Energy Committee (ITRE), where he updated Members of the Committee on the progress in implementing the EIT.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Parliament's",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Industry, Research and Energy Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Committee on the progress",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs)",
    "context": "\"The first seminar on the format of, and selection criteria for, the Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs), is held today in Bratislava, Slovak Republic. The KICs will be the operational parts of the European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT).\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the Knowledge and Innovation Communities",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bratislava",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Slovak Republic",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Institute of Innovation and Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('select', 0.9999999403953552)",
    "counterrole": "First 2-3 Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs)",
    "context": "\"The inaugural Board meeting has already been set for 15th September in Budapest and the Board's first major task will be the selection and launching of the first 2-3 Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs) by the end of 2009 / start of 2010.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Budapest",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('host', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Hungarian capital",
    "context": "\"On 18th June, EU Member States decided unanimously that the European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT) will have its headquarters in Budapest.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Institute of Innovation and Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Budapest",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('establish', 0.5383760333061218)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC, KIC InnoEnergy, EIT ICT Labs",
    "context": "\"Immediately afterwards, the Board will announce the two or three designated KICs.\" (YEAR: 2009)",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('launch', 0.6109565496444702)",
    "counterrole": "selection criteria",
    "context": "\"The EIT has today released the selection criteria for the first Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs).\" (YEAR: 2009)",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('establish', 0.5037422180175781)",
    "counterrole": "Gérard de Nazelle",
    "context": "\"The EIT Governing Board has appointed Gérard de Nazelle as first EIT Director.\" (YEAR: 2009)",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Gérard de Nazelle",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Board",
    "practice": "('deliver', 0.4547431170940399)",
    "counterrole": "draft rolling Triennial Work Programme",
    "context": "\"The EIT Board is pleased to announce that its first draft rolling Triennial Work Programme, which looks at EIT's short and medium term future, has been sent to the European Parliament, the Council and the Commission.\" (YEAR: 2009)",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "The EIT Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Triennial Work Programme",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Parliament",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Council",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Info Day",
    "context": "\"The EIT's Info Day, organised on 8 May in Wroclaw (Poland), was the occasion for potential KIC proposers to clarify remaining questions related to the call for Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs).\" (YEAR:",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wroclaw",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Commission",
    "practice": "('launch', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "context": "\"The European Commission launched the call for proposals for its first Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs) on Thursday 2 April 2009.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "The European Commission",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Various organizations (three thematic seminars)",
    "context": "\"The Board notably organized three thematic seminars in order to discuss with potential KIC proposers the focus of the three themes for the first KICs and their synergies with each other.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Union",
    "practice": "('introduce', 0.3998886048793793)",
    "counterrole": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "context": "\"As one of the European Union's flagship initiatives the EIT attracted representatives from Chinese universities, businesses and public authorities to discuss the importance of innovation in a knowledge economy.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the European Union's",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Vice Chairman",
    "practice": "('educate', 0.36633968353271484)",
    "counterrole": "Shanghai World EXPO participants",
    "context": "\"Anders Flodström, Vice Chairman of the EIT, explains why the EIT is one of them: 'The EIT is a European initiative with a clear international vocation. We want to be world-class in innovation - and you cannot be world class by just looking inward'.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Commission Director General",
    "practice": "('work', 0.4140273332595825)",
    "counterrole": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "context": "\"Jan Truszczyński, Director General for Education and Culture at the European Commission, stressed the novelty of the EIT as the first European initiative to fully integrate actors from innovation, research and education: 'With the EIT's Knowledge and Innovation Communities we want to be pioneers for changing the innovation landscape in",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the European Commission",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Knowledge and Innovation Communities",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('select', 0.4851638674736023)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "Gerard de Nazelle, EIT Director, has decided to leave the EIT as of 1 September 2010 due to personal reasons.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Gerard de Nazelle",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('offer', 0.6464191675186157)",
    "counterrole": "Dr. Martin Schuurmans",
    "context": "Dr Martin Schuurmans, Chairman of the EIT Governing Board, was invited to take part in the 8th European Business Summit (EBS) as a panellist.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the EIT Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "European Business Summit",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EBS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('host', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "The EIT celebrated the official launch of the ‘Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs)' at the 'Launching the KICs - Delivering new solutions to the European innovation landscape' conference in Barcelona on 2-3 June 2010.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Barcelona",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('connect', 0.5385892391204834)",
    "counterrole": "Commission President José Manuel Barroso and Commissioner Androulla Vassiliou",
    "context": "EIT Chairman, Dr. Martin Schuurmans, EIT Director, Gérard de Nazelle, members of the EIT Governing Board and representatives of EIT's newly created 'Knowledge and Innovation Communities' met Commission President José Manuel Barroso and Commissioner Androulla Vassiliou.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gérard de Nazelle",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the EIT Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Commission",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('offer', 0.6464191675186157)",
    "counterrole": "Dr Martin Schuurmans",
    "context": "Dr Martin Schuurmans, Chairman of the EIT's Governing Board, was invited to the 2010 Innovation Summit organised by the Lisbon Council in Brussels on 5 March 20",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Innovation Summit",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Lisbon Council",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Brussels",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT ICT Labs",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Eco-Energy-Solutions",
    "context": "EIT ICT Labs Eindhoven Node Director Patrick Strating selected team Fairy Tale as the winner.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT ICT Labs",
    "practice": "('sponsor', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC",
    "context": "The EIT is pleased to announce its first EIT Entrepreneurship Award competition which it is organizing in close collaboration with its three Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs): Climate-KIC, EIT ICT Labs and KIC InnoEnergy.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT ICT Labs",
    "practice": "('mentor', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Entrepreneurship Award finalists",
    "context": "\"Mentoring is key for emerging companies. The connection to powerful executives in European industry will give credibility to entrepreneurs. It will hopefully help them get access to new clients, markets and to think big! This is how the EIT wants to leverage its network and",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Headquarters",
    "practice": "('host', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC Office",
    "context": "\"The EIT Headquarters based in Budapest has decided to host offices for the KICs. Yesterday the first KIC Office was inaugurated for Climate-KIC.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Budapest",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC Office",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('mentor', 0.3817653954029083)",
    "counterrole": "Alexander von Gabain",
    "context": "\"Martin Schuurmans, the first Chairman of the EIT Governing Board, passed on the strategic leadership of the institute to Alexander von Gabain on the occasion of today’s Board meeting.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the EIT Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "’s Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('fund', 0.4110508859157562)",
    "counterrole": "EIT",
    "context": "\"One of Alexander von Gabain’s immediate priorities will be to focus the EIT’s efforts on becoming a true innovation impact investor; a vision that is outlined in the EIT’s Strategic Innovation Agenda (SIA).\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SIA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "('create', 0.39868441224098206)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Roundtable of Top Entrepreneurs",
    "context": "\"The Governing Board welcomed the proposals put forward by the new EIT Director José Manuel Leceta including a service oriented EIT offices in Budapest and the setting up of a Corporate Forum, both of which will increase accountability and ultimately add value to the current KIC operations.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Budapest",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Corporate Forum",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Academy of Entrepreneurs",
    "context": "\"This is intended to serve as a platform for mutual inspiration and dialogue in the field of entrepreneurship and innovation between the EIT, its KICs, top level entrepreneurs and its stakeholder community.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Commission",
    "practice": "('launch', 0.7573521137237549)",
    "counterrole": "open public consultation on the European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "context": "\"The consultation was undertaken in order to provide the Commission with stakeholders' views on EIT's future priority areas and on its role in the European innovation landscape.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Commission",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Commission",
    "practice": "('offer', 0.3485201299190521)",
    "counterrole": "187 contributions to the consultation on the EIT",
    "context": "\"The Commission has received 187 contributions to the consultation on the EIT, 134 of which were submitted via the online questionnaire, and the remaining 53 in the form of written contributions.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Commission",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('establish', 0.7041229009628296)",
    "counterrole": "three Knowledge and Innovation Communities (Climate-KIC, EIT ICT Labs and KIC InnoEnergy)",
    "context": "\"In 2010, the EIT's three Knowledge and Innovation Communities (Climate-KIC, EIT ICT Labs and KIC InnoEnergy) took shape as organisations led by an independent management team and each defined their legal structure.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "InnoEnergy",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('set up', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Headquarters",
    "context": "\"The first activities of the EIT and its KICs, notably in the fields of higher education and entrepreneurship development were also started in 2010. To be continued... EIT Annual Report 2010.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT ICT Labs",
    "practice": "('found', 0.40846025943756104)",
    "counterrole": "22 start-ups to SLUSH",
    "context": "\"EIT ICT Labs brought 22 start-ups to SLUSH – the largest tech, design & start-up conference covering Northern Europe and Russia.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Russia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "KIC InnoEnergy",
    "practice": "('partner', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Swedish Royal Institute of Technology (KTH) and Ericsson",
    "context": "Within the activities of CC Sweden, the node for Smart Grids and Storage within KIC InnoEnergy, the Swedish Royal Institute of Technology (KTH) and Ericsson have collaborated to increase the reliability of electricity grids through the use of wireless information technology.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "CC Sweden",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Smart Grids",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC InnoEnergy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Swedish",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Royal Institute of Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KTH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "KIC InnoEnergy",
    "practice": "('enable', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "companies that own power grids and are responsible for the distribution of electricity between generators and consumers",
    "context": "KIC InnoEnergy is the key enabler in this type of project.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "InnoEnergy",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Ericsson",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "KIC InnoEnergy",
    "context": "The partnership has been built on the strengths of both the department of Industrial Information & Control Systems at KTH and Ericsson.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Industrial Information & Control Systems",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KTH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Ericsson",
    "practice": "('sponsor', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Ausgrid (energy company in Australia)",
    "context": "Ericsson has engaged Ausgrid to build a private LTE network.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Ausgrid",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "TeliaSonera",
    "practice": "('offer', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "power companies",
    "context": "Power companies could then use TeliaSonera or any other of the market’s mobile operators to provide wireless connectivity.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "TeliaSonera",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Commission",
    "practice": "('implement', 0.5172668099403381)",
    "counterrole": "European Parliament and Member States",
    "context": "\"The European Commission has proposed a budget of €3.2 billion for the EIT, as part of the Horizon 2020 programme for research and innovation. Horizon 2020 is currently being negotiated by the European Parliament and Member States.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "The European Commission",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Parliament",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Member States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Euronews' 'Generation y'",
    "practice": "('connect', 0.5385892391204834)",
    "counterrole": "group of young people in Paris",
    "context": "\"of these two days discuss how the EIT can contribute to addressing societal challenges. Euronews' 'Generation y' meets a group of young people in Paris, taking part in Climate-KIC's theJourney, who are learning how to make money while fighting global warming.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC's",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "theJourney",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 0.4649288058280945)",
    "counterrole": "public",
    "context": "\"The EIT's publication on practices emerging from its three current Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs) is published.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Knowledge and Innovation Communities",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('introduce', 0.3998886048793793)",
    "counterrole": "participants in Copenhagen",
    "context": "\"It is always a pleasure to see committed and bright innovators come together under the same roof and the EIT is proud to have brought together such participants in Copenhagen on 25 and 26 June.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Copenhagen",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Conference on ‘Good Practices and Learnings’",
    "practice": "('deliver', 0.4029247462749481)",
    "counterrole": "key questions",
    "context": "\"Within the framework of a wider discussion on the future of innovation policies and the integration of the knowledge triangle (business, research, higher education), the EIT was able to showcase its first achievements and increase understanding on how it can help advance innovation in Europe.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "collaborate",
    "counterrole": "KIC InnoEnergy",
    "context": "\"The Future Internet PPP and EIT ICT Labs will focus on ICT infrastructure, entrepreneurship, business development, education and training.\"\n\n2.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ICT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('fund', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Trifense",
    "context": "\"The EIT ICT Labs is a Knowledge and Innovation Community (KIC) of the European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT). It is a consortium of leading European universities, research centres and companies that work together to develop innovative solutions in the field of",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Institute of Innovation and Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT ICT Labs",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC, KIC InnoEnergy",
    "context": "\"It was the first time that more than 150 students and alumni from across Climate-KIC, EIT ICT Labs and KIC InnoEnergy met under one roof to share knowledge, develop ideas, and find partners for new initiatives.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "InnoEnergy",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 0.4649288058280945)",
    "counterrole": "Selection Criteria for the EIT’s 2014 Call for KICs",
    "context": "\"The EIT has today published the Selection Criteria for the EIT’s 2014 Call for KICs.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Selection Criteria",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs)",
    "context": "\"In addition, the EIT will set up new Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs) in the thematic fields of innovation for healthy living and active ageing, raw materials, food for future, added value manufacturing and urban mobility.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Knowledge and Innovation Communities",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "higher education institutions, research organisations, companies and other innovation stakeholders",
    "context": "\"The Regional Innovation Scheme will foster innovation across the Union by allowing partnerships of higher education institutions, research organisations, companies and other innovation stakeholders to collaborate closely with KICs.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Union",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC Switzerland",
    "practice": "('fund', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "South Pole Carbon",
    "context": "\"Five major European asset managers and asset owners are to have the carbon footprint of their investments analysed by Climate-KIC partner South Pole Carbon.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC Switzerland",
    "practice": "('implement', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "(SME) vouchers",
    "context": "\"It is also another implementation of (SME) vouchers by Climate-KIC Switzerland.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "SME",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Switzerland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC Switzerland",
    "practice": "('support', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "CDP",
    "context": "\"CDP, formerly known as the Carbon Disclosure Project, will provide further elaboration on the risks and details of the climate change governance and performance of companies within the portfolio.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "CDP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Carbon Disclosure Project",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('launch', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"The European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT) today celebrates innovation and entrepreneurship in Europe with a conference that will culminate with the announcement of the winners of the EIT Awards 2013.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "The European Institute of Innovation and Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the EIT Awards 2013",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT's Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs)",
    "practice": "('select', 0.9999999403953552)",
    "counterrole": "Chokri Moussaoui (Eternal Sun), David Tacconi (CoReHab), Dominik Peus (Antaco), Fabio Belloni (Quuppa), Héctor Martín (Smalle Technologies), Lars Wallden (Northstar Telemetrics), Lionel Chaverot (Enerstone) and Peter Stein (GreenTEG)",
    "context": "\"For the Venture Award, which puts the spotlight on breakthrough innovations and exciting start-ups, the following eight nominees have been selected by the EIT’s Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs).\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"To help realise its objective, the EIT organises an annual award competition that showcases entrepreneurial ideas and that puts the spotlight on entrepreneurial talent from its three KICs.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('initiate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"Launched in 2012, the EIT Awards highlight the ideas and start ups that are coming out of the EIT’s KICs.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"The EIT is an EU body set up in 20",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EU",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC, EIT ICT Labs, KIC InnoEnergy",
    "context": "\"In order to support this objective, the EIT organises an annual award competition in collaboration with its three KICs – Climate-KIC, EIT ICT Labs and KIC InnoEnergy - in two categories: The EIT Venture Award showcases entrepreneurial undertakings emerging from the KICs and supports them in their further development; The EIT Change Agents and Next Generation of Entrepreneurs (CH.A.N.G.E.) Award puts the spotlight on young entrepreneurial talent from EIT-labelled and KIC education and training programmes for their achievements in entrepreneurship, intrapreneurship and innovation.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "InnoEnergy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The EIT Venture Award",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The EIT Change Agents",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Next Generation of Entrepreneurs (CH.A.N.G.E.) Award",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('introduce', 0.6112282276153564)",
    "counterrole": "European Union Commissioner for Education, Culture, Youth and Sport, EIT Interim Director",
    "context": "\"Today, the EIT announced the winners of the call for EIT Health and EIT Raw Materials, integrated European partnerships of higher education, business and research aiming to tackle societal challenges across Europe.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Raw Materials",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('partner', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "European Business and Technology Centre (EBTC)",
    "context": "\"Climate-KIC has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with the European Business and Technology Centre (EBTC) in Bangalore, India this week. This partnership will support and promote European climate entrepreneurs in India.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the European Business and Technology Centre",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bangalore",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EBTC",
    "practice": "('provide', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC start-ups",
    "context": "\"EBTC provides services to our start-ups for their market introduction.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "award",
    "counterrole": "Spain, French National Institute of Health and Medical Research (Inserm), University of Oxford (UK)",
    "context": "\"We are thrilled to win the EIT’s call.\"\n\n2.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "partner",
    "counterrole": "RawMatTERS (sustainable exploration, extraction, processing, recycling and substitution)",
    "context": "\"RawMatTERS – winner of EIT Raw Materials\"\n\n3.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Raw Materials",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "RawMatTERS (sustainable exploration, extraction, processing, recycling and substitution)",
    "practice": "establish",
    "counterrole": "KGHM Polish Copper S.A. (Poland), RISE Research Institute of Sweden, University of Milano-Bicocca (Italy)",
    "context": "\"RawMatTERS brings together more than 100 partners from 20 EU Member States\"\n\n4.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EU",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "provide",
    "counterrole": "RawMatTERS (sustainable exploration, extraction, processing, recycling and substitution), EIT Health",
    "context": "\"The EIT will provide each of the winners with a start-up grant of up to 4 million EUR\"\n\n5.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EUR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European University Institute (EUI)",
    "practice": "collaborate",
    "counterrole": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "context": "\"To maximise the opportunities for co-operation, the EIT Director, José Manuel Leceta, will be personally and directly collaborating with the EUI in Florence to establish close links between the",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EUI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Florence",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT (European Institute of Innovation and Technology)",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "CEPOL (European Police College)",
    "context": "\"Understanding is to establish co-operation between CEPOL and the EIT following the re-location of CEPOL to Budapest on 1 October 2014.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "CEPOL",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CEPOL",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Budapest",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Innovation and Entrepreneurship event",
    "context": "\"The EIT organises annual awards to recognise and reward the successful start-ups, innovative projects and young entrepreneurial talent that Europe has to offer. The 2015 EIT Awards will be an integral part of the EIT Innovation and Entrepreneurship event that will be held in Budapest on 05 to 07 May 2015.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the EIT Innovation and Entrepreneurship",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Budapest",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('support', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "CEPOL",
    "context": "\"The agencies will support each other in the delivery of services, administration and logistics and exchange expertise and good practices to further improve their operations.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('incubate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "More than 450 business ideas",
    "context": "\"Since 2010, the KICs have incubated more than 450 business ideas and created 75 innovative start-ups.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('select', 0.9999999403953552)",
    "counterrole": "Two new KICs",
    "context": "\"At the end of this year, the EIT will select two new KICs in the fields of Raw Materials and Innovation for Healthy Living and Active Ageing further enlarging the EIT Community.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Raw Materials and Innovation for Healthy Living and Active Ageing",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the EIT Community",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('test', 0.3977481722831726)",
    "counterrole": "Proposals for new KICs",
    "context": "\"The EIT",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "initiate",
    "counterrole": "European Union",
    "context": "\"The European Union has played a key role in brokering today’s historic agreement in Paris\"\n\n2.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "The European Union",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Union",
    "practice": "build",
    "counterrole": "broad coalition of developed and developing countries",
    "context": "\"The European Union has been building a broad coalition of developed and developing countries in favour of high ambition that shaped the successful outcome of the Paris summit\"\n\n3.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "The European Union",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker",
    "practice": "send",
    "counterrole": "a clear signal",
    "context": "\"Today the world is united in the fight against climate change. Today the world gets a lifeline, a last chance to hand over to future generations a world that is more stable, a healthier planet, fairer societies and more prosperous economies\"\n\n4.",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Bertrand van Ee",
    "practice": "recall",
    "counterrole": "words",
    "context": "\"President Obama ended his speech at the opening of the COP21 climate change summit with ‘Let’s get to work.’ I would now like to recall those words on the day of the historic Paris Agreement\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('create', 0.44363075494766235)",
    "counterrole": "Various organizations",
    "context": "\"Climate-KIC has already spawned a range of those cutting-edge innovations, from climate change mitigation technologies, such as carbon negative power technology Cogent Heat Energy Storage Systems (CHESS), through to Aqysta, a hydro-powered irrigation pump that can double crop yields in developing countries, without using any fuel or electricity.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Cogent Heat Energy Storage Systems",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aqysta",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EU Climate Action and Energy Commissioner Miguel Arias Cañete",
    "practice": "('provide', 0.38403576612472534)",
    "counterrole": "Global community",
    "context": "\"Europe has led the efforts in Paris to get an ambitious and legally binding global climate deal.”",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('provide', 0.4031387269496918)",
    "counterrole": "European business leaders",
    "context": "\"Last week, newly released research from Climate-KIC revealed that most European business leaders have prepared strategies to respond to climate change, but with a lack of focus on innovation.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Paris climate change agreement",
    "practice": "('connect', 0.3854314386844635)",
    "counterrole": "Today's policies and climate-neutrality before the end of the century",
    "context": "\"The Paris climate change agreement is a bridge between today’s policies and climate-neutrality before the end of the century.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Governments",
    "practice": "(None, 0.2324037253856659)",
    "counterrole": "Ambition, commitment, and solidarity",
    "context": "\"In Paris, governments agreed on ambition, commitment, and solidarity.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Governments",
    "practice": "('deliver', 0.3914594054222107)",
    "counterrole": "Comprehensive national climate action plans",
    "context": "\"Before and during the Paris conference, countries submitted comprehensive national climate action plans to reduce their emissions.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Governments",
    "practice": "('set up', 0.5154198408126831)",
    "counterrole": "More ambitious targets",
    "context": "\"To achieve this common amb",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "amb",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "award",
    "counterrole": "EIT CHANGE Award winner",
    "context": "\"The EIT CHANGE Award winner will receive € 15 000.\"\n\n2.",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "European Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "award",
    "counterrole": "EIT Innovators Award winner",
    "context": "\"EIT Innovators Award winner will receive € 50 000.\"\n\n3.",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "European Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "award",
    "counterrole": "EIT Venture Award winners",
    "context": "\"EIT Venture Award winners will receive € 50 000.\"\n\n4.",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Hans Joachim ‘John’ Schellnhuber, Climate-KIC’s chairman and director of Climate-KIC partner the Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research (PIK)",
    "practice": "advocate",
    "counterrole": "global community",
    "context": "\"Schellnhuber said: “If sincerely operationalised, the Paris agreement will induce the decarbonisation of the world economy by the middle of this century.”\"\n\n5.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Bertr a nd v a n Ee, CEO of Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "mobilize",
    "counterrole": "business",
    "context": "\"Van Ee said: “The deal struck in Paris today has unlocked a blue ocean of uncontested opportunities for business.”\"\n\n6.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Paris",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "incubate",
    "counterrole": "start-ups",
    "context": "\"Last year 40 Climate-KIC start-ups won funding of over €1 million, with one entrepreneur, t",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC's community",
    "context": "\"Climate-KIC’s experience as Europe’s largest collaboration community on climate change is that greater sharing of information can actually raise more competition, not limit it.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT",
    "practice": "('launch', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Two new Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs): EIT Food and EIT Manufacturing",
    "context": "\"Today, the EIT has published the Framework of Guidance for the EIT’s 2016 Call for KIC proposals. To further enhance its impact and to incentivise the innovations needed to meet societal challenges, we’re continuing to expand our activities in 2016 by launching a call for two new Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs): EIT Food: ensuring a climate-resilient and sustainable global food value chain EIT Manufacturing: strengthening and increasing the competitiveness of Europe’s manufacturing industry.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Framework of Guidance",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Knowledge and Innovation Communities",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Food",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Manufacturing",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Alumni Community",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Startup teams in Amsterdam, Paris, Berlin, Stockholm, and Barcelona",
    "context": "\"Over a hundred entrepreneurs gathered across five cities 6-8 November to take part in a Europe-wide competition organised by the EIT Alumni Community to find a winning startup idea.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the EIT Alumni Community",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Alumni",
    "practice": "('initiate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC",
    "context": "\"Inspirational entrepreneurs Motivation for change-making was the leading influencer as the entrepreneurs pitched their ideas.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Motivation",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Alumni",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "various startup teams",
    "context": "\"The weekend culminated with the teams pitching their completed business plans to the jury teams in each city.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Business mentors",
    "practice": "('support', 0.45264941453933716)",
    "counterrole": "various startup teams",
    "context": "\"Business mentors joined the teams to give them professional advice on how to turn a great idea into something profitable, and to provide words of encouragement.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Australia and New Zealand",
    "context": "\"At the COP21 climate change summit in December, the EU will be pushing for a binding deal that commits countries around the world to phase out fossil fuels and reduce carbon emissions. Leading up to the summit, some of the continent’s leading innovators are spreading the word around the world about the unprecedented opportunity to create a prosperous zero carbon future, driven by innovation, jobs, and investment. Climate-KIC’s international ambassador is one of them.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Climate-KIC International Ambassador (Mary Ritter)",
    "practice": "('initiate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Australia and New Zealand",
    "context": "\"Following almost four years at the helm as CEO at Climate-KIC from 2010, Ritter was in Australia at the end of 2014 in her new capacity as international ambassador, to meet with Climate-KIC partner Suncorp. “The idea began to germinate that perhaps we should think about being ambitious in the Austral",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Suncorp",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "launch",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"Today, the EIT is launching the call for expression of interest for the selection of four appointed members of the EIT Governing Board.\"\n\n2.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the EIT Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "appoint",
    "counterrole": "European Commission",
    "context": "\"The new members of the EIT Governing Board are to be appointed by the European Commission in summer 2016.\"\n\n3.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the EIT Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Commission",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Steering Committee",
    "practice": "oversee",
    "counterrole": "Selection of four new members of the EIT Governing Board",
    "context": "\"A steering committee will be in charge of identifying a list of potential candidates for the EIT Governing Board that will replace four current members whose term of office is coming to an end.\"\n\n4.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the EIT Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Steering Committee",
    "practice": "guarantee",
    "counterrole": "Independence, legitimacy, and credibility of the selection process",
    "context": "\"The Steering Committee will guarantee the independence, legitimacy and credibility of the selection process for four new members of the EIT Governing Board.\"\n\n5.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "The Steering Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the EIT Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "entrusted with",
    "counterrole": "Providing strategic leadership of the Institute",
    "context": "\"The EIT Governing Board is entrusted with providing the strategic leadership of the Institute.\"\n\n6.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Governing Board",
    "practice": "responsible for",
    "counterrole": "Selection, designation, and evaluation of the EIT’s Knowledge and Innovation Communities (KICs)",
    "context": "\"It is in particular responsible for the selection, designation and evaluation",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "European Commission",
    "practice": "('award', 0.5124731063842773)",
    "counterrole": "Governing Board",
    "context": "\"The four new members of the Governing Board will then be nominated by a European Commission Decision expected in summer 2016.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the Governing Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "a European Commission Decision",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Ulf Johansson",
    "practice": "('provide', 0.49318140745162964)",
    "counterrole": "Chairman of the Board of Ericsson",
    "context": "\"In 2005, he was appointed Chairman of the Board of Ericsson.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "the Board of Ericsson",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Jana Kolar",
    "practice": "('found', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Morana rtd",
    "context": "\"Dr. Jana Kolar is the founder of Morana rtd.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Morana",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Marja Makarow",
    "practice": "('provide', 0.49318140745162964)",
    "counterrole": "Vice-President of the Academy of Finland",
    "context": "\"Marja Makarow is vice-president of the Academy of Finland, the Finnish research council, since 2012.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Marja Makarow",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Academy of Finland",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology EIT",
    "practice": "('establish', 0.5037422180175781)",
    "counterrole": "Marja Makarow",
    "context": "\"Marja Makarow is a Member of the Governing Board of the European Institute of Innovation and Technology EIT since 2012.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Marja Makarow",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Governing Board of the European Institute of Innovation and Technology EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Mukul Kumar",
    "practice": "(None, 0.2324037253856659)",
    "counterrole": "LEDSafari",
    "context": "\"He was very happy with our work and agreed to become our CEO.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "LEDSafari",
    "practice": "('partner', 0.7614632248878479)",
    "counterrole": "EIT (European Institute of Innovation and Technology)",
    "context": "\"The EIT actually encouraged us to enter the competition.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "LEDSafari",
    "practice": "('offer', 0.3485201299190521)",
    "counterrole": "Forbes magazine",
    "context": "\"Forbes liked us and invited us over to Philadelphia.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Philadelphia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "LEDSafari",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 0.811797559261322)",
    "counterrole": "Pratt Foundation",
    "context": "\"They told us they loved our project and our unique approach, which was very nice to hear.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "LEDSafari",
    "practice": "('join', 0.4504835307598114)",
    "counterrole": "KIC InnoEnergy Master Programme",
    "context": "\"The KIC InnoEnergy Master programme was one year at the KTH Royal Institute of Technology in Stockholm and\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "InnoEnergy Master",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the KTH Royal Institute of Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Stockholm",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "LEDSafari",
    "practice": "('join', 0.7450934648513794)",
    "counterrole": "Climate-KIC Innovate4Climate Accelerator",
    "context": "\"We have also been part of the Climate-KIC Innovate4Climate Accelerator.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health Spain",
    "practice": "('award', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Multibioim",
    "context": "\"The winning project in the PoC category is Multiparametric nosological images for supporting clinical decision in solid tumors (Multibioim) of Elies Fuster Garcia of the Polytechnic University of Valencia;\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "PoC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Multiparametric",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Elies",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Polytechnic University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health Spain",
    "practice": "('award', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Novel antimicrobial therapy",
    "context": "\"In the PoC + category is Novel antimicrobial therapy by Eduard Torrents, from the Institute of Bioengineering of Catalonia (IBEC)\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "PoC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Novel",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Institute of Bioengineering of",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health Spain",
    "practice": "('award', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "UsMIMA",
    "context": "\"In the category HS the company UsMIMA, for the project TeDeMoOCC: Testing and Re-design of the prototype of MOWoOT, a medical device as a solution for chronic constipation.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "HS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "UsMIMA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('finance', 0.9999999403953552)",
    "counterrole": "Testing and Re-design of the prototype of MOWoOT, a medical device as solution for Chronic Constipation (TeDeMoOCC) from usMIMA",
    "context": "\"Head Start projects (funded with 50.000 € each)\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('finance', 0.9999999403953552)",
    "counterrole": "Clinical and technological validation of the SimVis Technology for cataract surgery (SimVisVal) from 2Eyes Vision",
    "context": "\"Head Start projects (funded with 50.000 € each)\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('finance', 0.9999999403953552)",
    "counterrole": "Oral Biofilter from Astradentium Health Technologies",
    "context": "\"Head Start projects (funded with 50.000 € each)\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('join', 0.6423434019088745)",
    "counterrole": "Participants",
    "context": "\"Registration is now open for the event, which is expected to include about 300 participants.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Health Matchmaking event in Uppsala, Sweden",
    "context": "\"The gathering is expected to generate hundreds of one-to-one meetings that can lead to fruitful partnerships.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "InnoStars",
    "practice": "('join', 0.6423434019088745)",
    "counterrole": "Participants from InnoStars countries and other RIS eligible countries outside EIT Health",
    "context": "\"StarShip is recruiting participants for its fellowship program (StarShip) from InnoStars countries and other RIS eligible countries outside EIT Health\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "InnoStars",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "RIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "InnoStars",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "University of Coimbra and IESE Business School and the Royal Institute of Technology (KTH)",
    "context": "\"Using a blend of different educational approaches including elements from Stanford Biodesign Concept, StarShip will be a unique opportunity for participants to be involved in industry-driven life science innovation, working together with innovators in and outside the companies in highly skilled multidisciplinary teams.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Stanford Biodesign Concept",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "InnoStars",
    "practice": "('develop', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Market-relevant products or services in collaboration with the industrial partner",
    "context": "\"During the one-year long programme, fellows learn a proven, action-based approach to find solution to industry challenges, verifying user requirements and identifying potentially unmet needs in the health context, in close collaboration with key industrial players and leading local EIT Health innovating institutions.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Digital",
    "practice": "('mobilize', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "European partners",
    "context": "\"EIT Digital is about filling the gap between knowledge and the market\" said Roberto Saracco, EIT Digital Italy Node Director, \"Accelerating scaleups and bringing innovative products to the market is our main focus. We help scaleups in accessing new markets and funding not only in Europe, but, through our hub in San Francisco, internationally as well.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Digital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Italy",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "San Francisco",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('coordinate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Steering Committee",
    "context": "\"Paragon Europe are now co-ordinating a Steering Committee which will implement plans agreed with Minister for Sustainable Development, the Environment and Climate Change Dr. José Herrera around the major themes for the conference: mobility and decarbonisation, circular economy, urbanisation and financial instruments to achieve the planned actions.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Steering Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Paragon Europe",
    "practice": "('introduce', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Attendees",
    "context": "\"Paragon Europe, with the support of EIT Climate-KIC, held a very well attended event at the International Press Club Association in Brussels last week. The event introduced a major climate change conference being held under the auspices of the Maltese Presidency of the Council of Europe in May 2017.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the International Press Club Association",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Brussels",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Council of Europe",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Paragon Europe",
    "practice": "('operate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Event",
    "context": "\"The event entitled “Climate Change Challenges in the Mediterranean under Malta’s EU Presidency” was opened by Paragon Europe chairman Edwin Ward who stated that if global warming continues on its upward path, and if climate change is not mitigated by reducing global greenhouse gas emissions, within the next 30 years, Malta could be very different to how we know it today.\"\n\nRole",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Paragon Europe",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Malta",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Nerdalize",
    "context": "\"Nerdalize, a Climate-KIC alumni start-up announced their plans for expanding their collaboration with Eneco on Wednesday 7 December in the presence of Prime Minister Mark Rutte.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Eneco",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('support', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Dr Richard Tunstall",
    "context": "\"Dr Richard Tunstall is helping to train the next generation of European entrepreneurs through his work embedding enterprise and innovation into the university curriculum. He took some time out of his busy schedule to chat to us about his experiences with innovation and entrepreneurship.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('fund', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "ClimateLaunchpad start-ups",
    "context": "\"EIT Climate-KIC might help you develop your idea. If your idea is less developed but all about an all-out mind shift in urban mobility, a sustainable transition in the food chain or any other way to tackle climate change: make sure to apply for our our ClimateLaunchpad programme.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ClimateLaunchpad",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('connect', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "European entrepreneurs",
    "context": "\"EIT Climate-KIC helps the most promising start-ups connect with the best experts, to formulate your business plan, to develop your entrepreneurial skills and fund your business through the early stages with its Acceleration Programme.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Acceleration Programme",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('educate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "students",
    "context": "\"Dr Richard Tunstall is helping to train the next generation of European entrepreneurs through his work embedding enterprise and innovation into the university curriculum.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('implement', 0.45032650232315063)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"The Policy Officer will contribute to the EIT’s work programme and may carry out the following tasks: Policy Development Develop and implement the strategy and policy processes led by the EIT.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Policy Development Develop",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('support', 0.41284680366516113)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"The Policy Officer will contribute to the EIT’s work programme and may carry out the following tasks: Policy Development Provide advice and\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('work', 0.4435097575187683)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"The Policy Officer will contribute to the EIT’s work programme and may carry out the following tasks: Policy Development Carry out tasks\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "European Institute of Innovation and Technology (EIT)",
    "practice": "('work', 0.5409602522850037)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"The Policy Officer will contribute to the EIT’s work programme and may carry out the following tasks: Policy Development Contribute to the EIT’s work programme\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Policy Development Contribute",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "London Waste And Recycling Board (LWARB)",
    "practice": "('innovate', 0.34063720703125)",
    "counterrole": "N/A",
    "context": "\"LWARB LWARB, who are tasked with driving the development of the circular economy in London, used the event to look for start-ups and ideas to play a part in the process.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "London",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('launch', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "UN’s Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO)",
    "context": "\"A new EIT Climate-KIC supported capacity-building tool for climate-smart agriculture (CSA) was launched this week at the headquarters of the UN’s Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO) in Rome.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CSA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the UN’s Food and Agriculture Organisation",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Rome",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('fund', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "CIRAD and INRA, France’s top agricultural research institutions",
    "context": "\"The tool, called Agrisource, is Europe’s first open innovation platform (OIP) for climate-smart agriculture, developed by CIRAD and INRA, France’s top agricultural research institutions and funded by EIT Climate-KIC ’s flagship programme CSA Booster, supported by EIT, a body of the European Union.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Agrisource",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "INRA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "France",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Climate-KIC ’s",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CSA Booster",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Union",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('support', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "International actors including businesses, research institutions, farmers, cooperatives, investors, NGOs, policy-makers and start-ups",
    "context": "\"Agrisource will bring together international actors including businesses, research institutions, farmers, cooperatives, investors, NGOs, policy-makers and start-ups in a virtual environment to map, connect and stimulate debate on innovative CSA technologies and solutions, acting as a catalyst and hub for new regional and international projects.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "cooperatives",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CSA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC",
    "practice": "('connect', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Agrisource platform",
    "context": "\"It will be a key resource for those seeking information or innovation, and a network hub for people with new ideas for climate change mitigation and adaptation from agrifood value chains.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "CSA Booster",
    "practice": "('facilitate', 0.5507602095603943)",
    "counterrole": "Agrisource platform",
    "context": "'As the EU regional alliance for the FAO’s Global Alliance for Climate-Smart Agriculture (GACSA), it will actively promote engagement across its ecosystem of expert research communities and innovation networks to drive engagement and uptake of the new Agrisource platform.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "FAO’s Global Alliance for Climate-Smart Agriculture",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Agrisource's lead developer Marc Nougier of INRA",
    "practice": "('offer', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "a new, systemic approach to climate change",
    "context": "'Agrisource is a new capacity-building tool at the crossroads of knowledge and networks in CSA. It offers a new, systemic approach to climate change, combining a powerful search engine with community-created content, to drive innovation, communication, partnerships and knowledge-sharing.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "CSA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Co-developer and Agrisource technical lead Jean-Baptiste Laurent of CIRAD",
    "practice": "('build', 0.4853035807609558)",
    "counterrole": "this platform to serve the needs of entire agrifood value chains",
    "context": "'We designed this platform to serve the needs of entire agrifood value chains[tweetable], from labs and research communities to retail brands and farmers and the field players of agriculture who together are the creators and guardians of climate-smart agriculture.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Digital Challenge Lead",
    "practice": "('award', 0.3574967384338379)",
    "counterrole": "Europe's most promising scale-ups in the field of deep technologies",
    "context": "'The EIT Digital Challenge aims to identify Europe's most promising scale-ups in the field of deep technologies (deep tech) - complex and disruptive solutions that are built around unique and differentiated scientific or technological advances.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Scottish Enterprise",
    "practice": "('invest', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "PhysioMedics",
    "context": "'Scottish Enterprise, through the Scottish Investment Bank, is delighted to be co-investing with Archangels to allow the company to develop and commercialise PhysioWizard.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Scottish Enterprise",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Scottish Investment Bank",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Archangels",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Archangels",
    "practice": "('provide', 0.38403576612472534)",
    "counterrole": "PhysioMedics",
    "context": "'A year ago, PhysioWizard raised GBP 250 000 of seed funding and has now received a further GBP 750 000, in a funding round led by Archangels,'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "PhysioWizard",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Archangels",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "PhysioMedics",
    "practice": "('develop', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "PhysioWizard",
    "context": "'The company is already working with large health insurance providers to implement the system in early 2018.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "PhysioMedics",
    "practice": "('train', 0.31538495421409607)",
    "counterrole": "PhysioWizard",
    "context": "'The company is already working with large health insurance providers to implement the system in early 2018.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "PhysioMedics",
    "practice": "('finance', 0.33184725046157837)",
    "counterrole": "PhysioMedics",
    "context": "'The company is already working with large health insurance providers to implement the system in early 2018.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "PhysioMedics",
    "practice": "('implement', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "large health insurance providers",
    "context": "'The company is already working with large health insurance providers to implement the system in early 2018.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "PhysioMedics",
    "practice": "('innovate', 0.4870658218860626)",
    "counterrole": "US and Australia",
    "context": "'PhysioMedics has come a long way in 12 months and this funding will enable us not only to develop our commercial platform but also explore opportunities in the US and Australia,'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "PhysioMedics",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "US",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT InnoEnergy",
    "practice": "('partner', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "MOL Group",
    "context": "'Our start-ups gain direct access and the ability to work with a leading international player. MOL in turn invests in the largest open innovation platform in the cleantech sector in the world, with a particular focus on MOL’s strategic area of ​​Central Eastern Europe.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "MOL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT InnoEnergy",
    "practice": "('support', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "ThingWave",
    "context": "'ThingWave, a start-up supported by EIT RawMaterials, provides solutions for real-time and online rock bolt monitoring.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT RawMaterials",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "MOL Group",
    "practice": "('sponsor', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT InnoEnergy",
    "context": "'MOL Group was the main sponsor of the PowerUp! start-up competition, organized by EIT InnoEnergy Central Europe.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "MOL Group",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PowerUp",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT InnoEnergy Central Europe",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "MOL Group",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT InnoEnergy",
    "context": "'MOL Group will become an active participant of the EIT InnoEnergy community, taking part in prestigious industry events, training programs, and prioritizing collaboration with innovators.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "MOL Group",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "MOL Group",
    "practice": "('invest', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT InnoEnergy",
    "context": "'MOL in turn invests in the largest open innovation platform in the cleantech sector in the world, with a particular focus on MOL’s strategic area of ​​Central Eastern Europe.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "MOL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "MOL Group",
    "practice": "('join', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "EIT InnoEnergy community",
    "context": "'MOL Group will become an active participant of the EIT InnoEnergy community.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "MOL Group",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Digital",
    "practice": "('sponsor', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Lexplore",
    "context": "'With the EIT Digital Accelerator, we will now support Lexplore to expand internationally and make their method available to more people in Europe and beyond.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lexplore",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Digital",
    "practice": "('award', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Lexplore",
    "context": "'Lexplore has won first prize in the Digital Wellbeing category of the annual EIT Digital Challenge.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Digital Wellbeing",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Digital Challenge",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Lexplore",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Digital",
    "context": "'Winning would give us a lot credibility and trust. And we did indeed obtain the best possible endorsement for our solution as EIT Digital believed in us and chose us as the winner,'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Digital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "us",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Lexplore",
    "practice": "('educate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "schools",
    "context": "'Lexplore conducts the tests on school premises, taking only a few minutes per student.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Lexplore",
    "practice": "('provide', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "authorized users",
    "context": "'The results reveal clearly which students are either at risk or not for the condition.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Lexplore",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "secure web portal",
    "context": "'The information on the web portal is secure and encrypted, and all data is handled in accordance with the applicable information privacy regulations.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "Lexplore",
    "practice": "('set up', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Digital",
    "context": "'Thanks to us participating in the EIT Digital Challenge, we have a lot of new contacts'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Digital Accelerator",
    "practice": "('invest', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Sentryo",
    "context": "\"The EIT Digital Accelerator is proud to have its alumnus French scale-up, Sentryo, making a huge step forward with raising EUR 10 million in a Series A fundraising.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Digital",
    "practice": "('educate', 0.3684585690498352)",
    "counterrole": "Sentryo",
    "context": "\"Since the beginning, EIT Digital had understood the very high potential of Sentryo.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Digital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sentryo",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Sentryo",
    "practice": "('deliver', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "corporates",
    "context": "\"Sentryo delivers an operational security capacity to prevent, detect and respond to cyber-attacks.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('accelerate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "SyNoesis Therapeutics Ltd., LIfT BioSciences Ltd., Gedea Biotech AB, Sleepiz, NeuroPsyAI, FeetMe, Aenitis Technologies, VitaDX International, HydrUStent, Opsyon, Smart Medical Optics",
    "context": "'The winners were chosen in the three categories of Biotech, Medtech and Digital Health The winners of the European Health Catapult Business Plan Competition – in the three categories of Biotech, Medtech and Digital Health – were chosen by a professional jury following pitches by nine finalists at the EIT Health Summit, in Łódź (Poland), on 4 December 2018.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Biotech",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Digital Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Health Catapult Business Plan Competition",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Biotech",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Digital Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the EIT Health Summit",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Łódź",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('initiate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Various regional representations – the CLCs and InnoStars",
    "context": "'The competition began early this year, when a host of applicants were screened by EIT Health regional representations – the CLCs and InnoStars – and accepted into regional competitions.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "InnoStars",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('organize', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Various start-ups",
    "context": "'Following coaching, 42 regional winners went to the semifinals competitions: the Biotech contest in Leuven, Netherlands; Medtech in Grenoble, France; and Digital Health in Erlangen, Germany.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Biotech",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Leuven",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Netherlands",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Grenoble",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "France",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Digital Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Erlangen",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('advocate', 0.45673510432243347)",
    "counterrole": "Various start-ups",
    "context": "'They were judged based on the market readiness and anticipated impact of their healthcare innovations, and the most promising 22 start-ups were invited to compete in the finals during the 4-5 December 2018 E",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Food",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "13 organizations (Croatia, Czech Republic, Estonia, Greece, Hungary, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, Portugal, Romania, Slovakia, Slovenia, Turkey)",
    "context": "EIT Food is looking for 13 organisations that would assume the role of EIT Food Hubs in 13 countries, targeted by EIT Food’s Regional Innovation Scheme",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Food",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Food Hubs",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Food’s Regional Innovation Scheme",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT RIS",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 0.5367119312286377)",
    "counterrole": "EIT Community",
    "context": "The EIT RIS was introduced in 2014 to share good practices and experience emerging from EIT Community activities and to widen participation in our activities across Europe",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "RIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Community",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "Fairphone",
    "practice": "('create', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Social enterprise",
    "context": "Fairphone is a social enterprise that is building a movement for fairer electronics, to raise awareness among consumers on production processes",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT InnoEnergy and Schneider Electric",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Each other",
    "context": "EIT InnoEnergy and Schneider Electric announced the completion of a two-year collaboration to industrialise and commercialise PowerTag NSX",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT InnoEnergy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Schneider Electric",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PowerTag",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "JA Europe and EIT RawMaterials",
    "practice": "('partner', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Each other",
    "context": "A new innovative partnership between JA Europe and EIT RawMaterials has been launched to equip 1200 young people, aged 15-18, from Bulgaria and Romania, with entrepreneurship and STEM skills, and spark their interest in the raw materials sector.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT RawMaterials",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bulgaria",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Romania",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "STEM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC partners",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "cities of Edinburgh, London, Birmingham, Frankfurt, and Valencia",
    "context": "'We’re all familiar with the way in which clusters of complementary start-ups and skilled workers can drive commercial growth—Silicon Valley is a classic example. EIT Climate-KIC believes the emergence of broader city region-based innovation clusters focused specifically on climate could be key to meeting our emissions targets and delivering local economic benefits. Our aim is to explore how best to accelerate these wider ecosystems—that bring together businesses, academics, communities and governments to deliver on low carbon solutions—in our own city regions and others across Europe.'\n\nThe innovation project",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Climate-KIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "broader city region",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Digital and its European partners",
    "practice": "('launch', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "the Virtual Training Doctor",
    "context": "'Medical consultations have a small time limit, and elderly people in particular can find it difficult to ask the right questions about their conditions, which can make it difficult to get the best treatment. The EIT Digital innovation called the Virtual Training Doctor lets patients practice conversations beforehand in order to be better prepared for visits to the doctor.'\n\nThe collaboration",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "JA Europe and EIT RawMaterials",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 0.5407248139381409)",
    "counterrole": "European policymakers",
    "context": "'Experts indicate that almost all of the thirty fastest-growing occupations in the next decade will require at least some background in STEM, and this collaboration intends to raise awareness about the importance of entrepreneurship and STEM education among local and European policymakers.'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "STEM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "STEM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Climate-KIC’s Urban Transitions work",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "cities and regions",
    "context": "'Cities and regions can’t tackle these challenges alone. They need to bring people together across sectors and industries—from start-ups to big business, researchers, municipal authorities and communities themselves.'",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health InnoStars",
    "practice": "('establish', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "three new EIT RIS hubs – in Croatia, Czech Republic and Latvia",
    "context": "'The Supervisory Board of EIT Health InnoStars has approved the selection of the following new EIT Regional Innovation Scheme (RIS) hubs, which will join the EIT Health network: Image University of Zagreb, Croatia DEX Innovation Centre, Czech Republic Rīga Stradiņš University, Latvia'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "The Supervisory Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Health InnoStars",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "RIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Image University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Croatia DEX Innovation Centre",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Czech Republic",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Latvia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT InnoEnergy",
    "practice": "('host', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "COP24 UN Climate Change Conference",
    "context": "'A session entitled “Electrification of mobility” was organised by EIT InnoEnergy and Eurelectric at the UN COP24, on 4 December in Katowice (Poland)'",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT InnoEnergy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Eurelectric",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "UN",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Katowice",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health and Urban Mobility",
    "practice": "('organize', 0.5377798080444336)",
    "counterrole": "300 business angels, innovators, researchers, entrepreneurs, and policy makers",
    "context": "'On 25 and 26 November, 300 business angels, innovators, researchers, entrepreneurs, and policy makers came together in Brussels for the first edition of the European Angel Investment Summit, organised by the European Business Angel Network (EBAN) with its its co-organisers: the European Investment Project Portal (EIPP), the European Commission DG G",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Brussels",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Angel Investment Summit",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Business Angel Network",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Investment Project Portal",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIPP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the European Commission",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health",
    "practice": "('award', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Start-ups and SMEs",
    "context": "\"EIT Health recently announced their second round of Headstart 2019 funding, which will support 20 healthcare innovations. Start-ups backed with grants of up to EUR 50 000 each include different types of digital assistants, for doctors, nurses or intensive-care patients; ultrasound and medical imaging innovations; a new solution for bedsore prevention; microneedle patches for drug intake; improved tests for Parkinson’s and melanoma; and more.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Headstart",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "melanoma",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Food",
    "practice": "('partner', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "FAMAE",
    "context": "\"EIT Food recently joined forces with FAMAE, an independent family foundation based in France, that supports innovation in the field of environment. Every year, FAMAE organises an International Challenge to seek pragmatic, efficient, durable, universal and money-saving solutions to make life easier for urban citizens while reducing their environmental footprint. Their 2020 challenge is dedicated to Food: 'Food for Good'.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Food",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "FAMAE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "France",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "FAMAE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "International Challenge",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT InnoEnergy",
    "practice": "('finance', 0.9999999403953552)",
    "counterrole": "EcoBean",
    "context": "\"EcoBean, together with Warsaw University of Technology, has developed technology for the production of coffee briquettes from spent coffee grounds. The start-up has recently joined the EIT InnoEnergy ecosystem receiving comprehensive support with financial investment.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "Warsaw University of Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "FAMAE",
    "practice": "('offer', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Entrepreneurs, SMEs, students, researchers, farmers, NGOs and public bodies",
    "context": "\"This competition is for entrepreneurs, SMEs, students, researchers, farmers, NGOs and public bodies and covers the production, transformation,",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health Belgium-Netherlands",
    "practice": "('award', 0.8471069931983948)",
    "counterrole": "Aspect Analytics, CardiacBooster, Corporis Medical, Crescent Tech, Cue2Walk International, I-Med Technology, Kaminari Medical, MLA Diagnostics BV, MyLife Technologies, Sentomed, SkinBreeze, EIT Health Germany, Cliniserve, Clinomic GmbH, CogniScent",
    "context": "The 11 start-ups receiving funding under the second EIT Health Belgium-Netherlands Headstart call for 2019 were selected from a pool of 38 high-quality applicants.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Belgium",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Health Germany",
    "practice": "('award', 0.8471069931983948)",
    "counterrole": "Mindable Health, Vicron",
    "context": "However, the jury was so impressed with this year’s start-ups that EIT Health Germany made a decision to give out one more EUR 50 000 award, which was then split between two start-ups, Mindable Health and Vicron.",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT Health Germany",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mindable Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Urban Mobility Master School",
    "practice": "('train', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "Aalto University, KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Eindhoven University of Technology (TU/e), Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC) and Budapest University of Technology and Economics (BME)",
    "context": "\"The EIT Urban Mobility Master School will welcome the first students in September 2020.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Urban Mobility Master School",
    "practice": "(None, 0.2762954831123352)",
    "counterrole": "leading technological knowledge with training in innovation and entrepreneurship",
    "context": "\"The programmes integrate leading technological knowledge with training in innovation and entrepreneurship.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Urban Mobility Master School",
    "practice": "('educate', 1.0000001192092896)",
    "counterrole": "worldwide leaders in the urban mobility sector",
    "context": "\"The programme is aimed to educate worldwide leaders in the urban mobility sector.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Digital Master student, Mr Balázs Horváth",
    "practice": "('develop', 0.44152307510375977)",
    "counterrole": "European Commission Vice-President, Mr Margaritas Schinas",
    "context": "\"EIT Digital Master student, Mr Balázs Horváth, provided insights into the EIT's unique educational and entrepreneurial journey.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Digital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT RawMaterials supported RoStar project",
    "practice": "('develop', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "a prototype of an ultra-fine grinding mill",
    "context": "\"EIT RawMaterials supported RoStar project developed a prototype of an ultra-fine grinding mill.\"",
    "ner": [
      {
        "text": "RoStar",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "role": "RoStar prototype",
    "practice": "('develop', 0.42079848051071167)",
    "counterrole": "less energy compared to similar established mills",
    "context": "\"This mill consumes 20-30% less energy compared to similar established mills.\"",
    "ner": []
  },
  {
    "role": "EIT Community",
    "practice": "('collaborate', 1.0)",
    "counterrole": "Technische Universität Bergakademie Freiberg (TUBAF), Germany (Lead Partner)",
